Finding Aid for Information and Library Studies Student Association (University of Michigan) records, 1964-1994
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Information and Library Studies Student Association (University of Michigan) records 1964-1994
University of Michigan. Information and Library Studies Student Organization.
1.75 linear feet
87227 Bimu F22 2
Organization of graduate students enrolled in the Library School (later School of Information) at the University of Michigan. Records include minutes, newsletters, directories, secretary's books, and materials relating to library science.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records (Donor no. 5517 ) were transferred in several accessions.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
The Library Science student body was first organized when the Class of 1928 met and elected four officers. In 1957, the group was recognized as LSSO, the Library Science Student Organization. In 1964, organization business was presented to students at weekly convocations. In 1986, the organization changed its name to the School of Information and Library Studies Student Association (ILSSA) to correspond to the new title of the school. Since the early 1980's the organization has served more as a link between the student body and the administration. Before then, the organization served more as a social outlet for students. The name was changed again in 1988 to School of Information Student Association (SISA) when the School of Information and Library Studies became the School of Information.
The records of ILSSA measure 1 linear foot and are organized into three series: Administration, Miscellaneous Records, and Printed Material. The records include minutes, newsletters, directories, secretary's books, and materials relating to library science.
Subjects:
Libraries--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. School of Library Science.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.; University of Michigan. Information and Library Studies Student Organization.; University of Michigan. School of Information.
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Library Science Student Organization.
Genre/From:
Brochures.; Calendars.; Directories.; Newsletters.; Student publications.
- Administration Records
  The Administration records date from 1964 to 1991 and primarily consist of the Administrative records series which include: meeting notes, memos, announcements and flyers, constitution and bylaws, student directories, correspondence (limited), election statements, election forms and results, survey forms and results, annual and presidents reports, and list of resources for incoming students. The Administration Records series is arranged chronologically. There are no records available from 1984-1986.
  - 1964 (Box 1)
  - 1965 (Box 1)
  - 1966 (Box 1)
  - 1967 (Box 1)
  - 1968 (Box 1)
  - 1969 (Box 1)
  - 1970 (Box 1)
  - 1971 (Box 1)
  - 1972 (Box 1)
  - 1973 (Box 1)
  - 1974 (Box 1)
  - 1975 (Box 1)
  - 1976 (Box 1)
  - 1977 (Box 1)
  - 1978
    - White House Conference on Information and Library Services, (1978) (Box 1)
  - 1979 (Box 1)
  - 1980 (Box 1)
  - 1981 (Box 1)
  - 1982 (Box 1)
  - 1983 (Box 1)
  - 1987 (Box 1)
  - 1988 (Box 1)
  - 1989 (Box 1)
  - 1990 (Box 1)
  - 1991 (Box 1)
  - 1992 (meeting notes only) (Box 1)
  - 1993 (meeting notes only) (Box 1)
  - 1994 (meeting notes only) (Box 1)
  - Undated (most likely circa 1978) (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Records
  The Miscellaneous Records series includes histories of the organization, general information about ILSSA and the library studies program and datatape of an online discussion group. The folder labeled "Histories" contains a report dated 1971 describing the history of the organization from 1926 to 1971. Another two page report written in 1980 contains 2-3 sentence highlights concerning the organization's history and activities from 1928 to 1978.
  There are also two notebooks. "LSSO Information Collection: UM Information and Where to Get It" is a loose leaf note book containing brochure and maps of services and recreation at Ann Arbor and the University of Michigan. "Records, Activities, and Publications for the Year: 1974-1975" divide the contents listed in the title into three separate loose leaf collections. The notebook also contains a set of photographs.
  - Histories (Box 1)
  - LSSO Information Collection: UM Information and Where to Get It (Box 1)
  - ILSSA: Records, Activities, and Publications for the Year: 1974-1975. (Box 1)
  - Data tape
    - GCOT:CONFER and GCOT:INFORM (Box 1)
      (three volumes of the student computer conference maintained by ILSSA. Downloaded from the mainframe computer to IBM 3280 cartridge at 6250 bpi using CONFER archive and MTS filesave procedures. Log of download and other technical information is located in donor file. Cartridge is at B-31-M)
- Printed Materials
  - Brochures undated (Box 2)
  - Calendars
    - Clog Calendar
      - 1979-1982, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - ILSSA's Calendar of Events, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Directories
    - Biographical Directory: Class of 1965, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Student Directory, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Who's Here is Library Science
      - 1969/70-1976/77, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Who's Who in Room 110, 1951/52 (Box 2)
  - Newsletters
    - The Communicator
      - 1982-1993, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Crack in the Wall
      - 1974-1977, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - The Eclectic, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
    - LSSO Newsletter, 1968-1974 (Box 2)
    - News from ILSSA, 1992 (Box 2)
    - What It Is, 1977-1979 (Box 2)